

 \searrow

mailvaibhavchopra@gmail.co



+919319740960



Delhi, India



vaibhavchopra.ml



linkedin.com/in/vc2001



github.com/sudo-vaibhav



medium.com/@mailvaibhavch opra

SKILLS

AWS

Blockchain

DevOns

Docker

O.U.

GranhOl

IZ. da a wa a ta a

Linux

Microsoft Azure

MongoDB

PostgreSQL

Python

React

Tailwind

LANGUAGES

Enalish

Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

INTERESTS

Reading

Fitness

Gaming

Vaibhav Chopra

Software Engineer, Celo India Fellow, Student Researcher at Samsung Prism.

I'm a curious student of the art of Computer Science. I'm always ready to take up projects and determined to complete them successfully. I love to interact with people through webinars and mentoring in hackathons.

EDUCATION

B.Tech. CSE

Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore

07/2019 - Present

Current CGPA - 9.38/10

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Prisha Insurance Brokers Pvt. Ltd.

03/2021 - 04/2022

- Developed several applications responsible for vital operations from scratch.
- Spearheaded the use of cutting-edge technologies like GraphQL, Gatsby, MongoDB, React, and Progressive Web Apps to enhance developer and customer experience.
- Optimized the digital footprint and increased unique visitors by 50%.

Blockchain India Fellow

Celo

06/2021 - 08/2021

- Developed several decentralized applications involving using the WEB3 SDK.
- Contributed to open source and documenting core libraries using Storybook and Docusaurus.
- Conducted several presentations and talks on Celo.

ORGANIZATIONS AND VOLUNTEERING

Community Lead at Student Technical Community (STC-VIT) (03/2021 - 03/2022)

Streamlined processes leading to a 40% increase in technical project output and social media stats.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Solidity Push Notification Service - Push Notifications for Web3

Improved the User Experience of Ethereum-based blockchain applications. Analyzed the technical limitations and developed a thoroughly tested solution. Employed modern technologies like Solidity, Jest, Docusaurus, Kubernetes and Web Sockets. sudo-vaibhav/solidity-push-notification-service (github.com)

Smriti - Alzheimer's Patient Assistant App

Engineered a custom-made pair of glasses fitted with a camera module using Raspberry Pi for face detection along with a companion application built with Webpack and Typescript. Conducted a case study and devised an innovative solution to a widespread problem. sudo-vaibhav/smriti-app (github.com)

DCompute - A Decentralized WASM Powered Compute Marketplace

A project that tackles the semiconductor shortage and increasing cloud computing bills by allowing users to exchange their time and compute resources, through a platform powered by Web Assembly,
 AssemblyScript, React and Node JS. sudo-vaibhav/DCompute (github.com)

ACHIEVEMENTS

DevSoc-2021 by CodeChef - Best UI/UX and Rarible NFT Track Winner (05/2021)

A 36-hour international hackathon conducted by CodeChef VIT.

Hackout by Headout Winner - 3rd position worldwide (11/2020)

A 48-hour international virtual hackathon with over 750+ participants all across the globe.